# **SMITH KAMLESH GAJJAR**

# SENIOR FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# CONTACT

smith.gajjar@gmail.com

https://smithgajjar.dev

Mumbai, India.

# **SKILLS**

#### Languages & Frameworks

Node, GraphQL, React, Javascript TypeScript, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, NGINX, Electron, HTML, CSS/Sass, Angular, React Native.

#### **Tools & Platforms**

AWS, Azure, Sentry, Jenkins, Git, Webpack, Heroku, Vercel, Docker, Jest, Asana, Jira, Trello.

# **EDUCATION**

# BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2018 - 2021

Vivekanand Educational Society's Institute of Technology

# DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2015 - 2018

K.J.Somaiya Polytechnic

# SOCIAL

in Smith Gajjar

@smith.gajjar09

@smithg09

<u>blogs.smithgajjar.dev</u>

# **ABOUT**

Senior Full Stack Developer and Solutions Architect with a penchant for minimalistic design and optimizations. I have hands-on experience in developing applications using several javascript frameworks, managing and optimizing backend infrastructure including deployment, scalability, performance and efficiency.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **@TEKIE**

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER

June 2022- Present

**FULL STACK DEVELOPER** 

June 2021- June 2022

FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN

Feb 2021- June 2021

- ▶ Building user facing modules for MVP product, a Progressive Web App based on Reactjs and a Desktop Application using Electron.js
- Developing API's, Managing and optimizing backend architecture for enhanced scalability and performance utilizing Nodejs and GraphQL.
- ▶ Integration of different 3rd party services such as Sentry, Elastic Search and GA/GTM to improve application performance.
- Managing and optimizing infrastructure based on Kubernetes, Redis, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Azure Services and AWS Services such as EC2, EKS, ECR, S3 and CloudFront.
- ▶ Built supporting NPM libraries for MVP product, <u>mongodb-aggregation-builder</u>, <u>tekie-content-editor</u>, <u>tekie-blockly</u>
- > Interacting and engaging in discussions with stakeholders from various departments to determine and deliver optimal tech solutions aligned with business requirements.
- $\triangleright$  Leading a team of 7 in spearheading the development and seamless migration of an product suite

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER INTERN @INVIDEO

3rd June - 19th July 2019 // Mumbai, MH // @Experience Letter

- ightarrow Creating new user facing modules for MVP product based on Angular 7.
- ▶ Converting designs from InVision into pixel-perfect responsive screens.
- ▶ Helped in fixing cross-browser inconsistencies in the interface.

# **PROJECTS**

#### mongodb-aggregation-builder

NPM: mongodb-aggregation-builder
MongoDB Aggregation Pipeline constructor.

#### **Tekie-blockly NPM Library**

@npmjs.com/package/tekie-blockly
Customised Blockly Framework

#### **Flashify**

https://github.com/smithg09/Flashify
Flashcard Mobile App using React Native

#### Tekie-content-editor NPM Library

<u>npmjs.com/package/tekie-content-editor</u> Web based WYSIWYG editor library for React.

#### Covid19 Tracker

https://covid19.smithgajjar.dev/ ProgressiveWebApp for tracking COVID19

#### **GraphQL Nodejs Backend starter**

Repo: <u>nx-node-apollo-grahql-mongo</u>
Built using Typescript/MongoDB/GraphQL.

View all projects @https://github.com/smithg09